Joel Rivera

Senior Front-End Engineer

Contact information

joelrivera.me@gmail.com 407-994-8118

Skills

TypeScript		
React		
Remix		
Tailwindcss		

Links

My Website

GitHub

LinkedIn

Languages

English

Spanish

Professional summary

Senior Front-End Engineer boasting 10 years of experience, distinguished by a track record of building modern, Al-powered web applications. Having led initiatives to enhance code quality and web accessibility, this professional has also designed product demos securing significant revenue. Expertise in React, TypeScript, Tailwindcss, Remix, and Web Accessibility ensures delivery of visually appealing, inclusive, user-friendly interfaces.

Employment history

Front-End Dev Lead

Endava, Remote — Aug 2021 - Feb 2024

- I spearheaded a front-end testing overhaul for the Lineage Logistics LinOS Web apps team to define and establish testing best practices, documentation, and code examples. Increased code coverage from 0 to ~10% in less than 1 month.
- I actively contributed to fostering a culture of continuous learning, knowledge sharing, and mentorship for junior and mid-level front-end developers.
- I advocated for, and led initiatives to promote the awareness, importance, and practicality of web accessibility for professional, production-grade, inclusive web applications.

Senior Front-End Engineer

IBM, New York City - May 2015 - Feb 2021

- On the IBM DTE Solutions team, I designed and built flagship product demos for several Watson APIs like Watson Speech to Text, Watson NLU, and Watson Assistant, which helped IBM win over \$6 million in revenue from new client engagements.
- On the IBM Watson Prototypes team, I built Watson Al-powered web apps and interactive experiences for high profile clients like Starbucks, Geico, CNN, and Morgan Stanley.
- I collaborated with cross-functional teams to leverage cutting-edge technologies and innovative solutions to enhance user experiences and drive revenue growth for IBM's flagship products.

Front-End Developer

Morgan Stanley, New York City — Feb 2014 - Dec 2014

- Developed user-friendly front-end interfaces using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to enhance the user experience and meet the business requirements of Morgan Stanley's financial services applications.
- Built internal microsites, published quarterly earnings reports, and maintained morganstanley.com in production.

Education

Self-Taught Education, Remote — Feb 2012 - Present

I transitioned into a career in design and engineering through self-directed learning rather than a conventional Computer Science degree. My technical proficiency was honed through a combination of online educational platforms such as Pluralsight (formerly Code School), Codecademy, Treehouse, CSS Tricks, and MDN, along with practical experience gained from developing websites for local clients and engaging in personal side projects.